<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-14T08:13:37+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Analyst’s Notes</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Productivity Apps</title><link href="/blog/travel/2019/03/07/productivity-app.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Productivity Apps" /><published>2019-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/travel/2019/03/07/productivity-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/travel/2019/03/07/productivity-app.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evernote with its integration can be a perfect fit for those who wants to manage tasks disparating in multiple platforms. Note that for reminder feature, Evernote is applying in terms of each unit of notes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Keep is perfectly fit for those who mainly focus their tasks on GSuite. Also, the feature of reminding comes along with each G-Keep notes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trello is free and easy to use, especially for someone who want to manage their workload following a consistent workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hoang Nguyen</name></author><category term="hot" /><category term="summer" /><summary type="html">Evernote with its integration can be a perfect fit for those who wants to manage tasks disparating in multiple platforms. Note that for reminder feature, Evernote is applying in terms of each unit of notes. Google Keep is perfectly fit for those who mainly focus their tasks on GSuite. Also, the feature of reminding comes along with each G-Keep notes. Trello is free and easy to use, especially for someone who want to manage their workload following a consistent workflow</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">S.M.A.R.T.</title><link href="/2019/03/05/smart.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="S.M.A.R.T." /><published>2019-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2019/03/05/smart</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/03/05/smart.html">&lt;p&gt;Business Requirements identify very high level business needs to fix issues and support business opportunities. These are normally defined by executives and senior people in the organization and key decision makers. Business reqs are commonly expressed in terms of measurable objectives and outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Specific: this means the requirement wording is clear, concise, and unambiguous.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measurable: this means the requirement has a criteria which can be tested.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Achievable: this means the requirement can be successfully attained given project environment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Realistic: this means the requirement can be associated with a stakeholder, process, or system, function, model, design element; or test document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To deliver the stakeholder requirement we’ll need to detail the solution requirements, and these are split into functional requirements and nonfunctional requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hoang Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html">Business Requirements identify very high level business needs to fix issues and support business opportunities. These are normally defined by executives and senior people in the organization and key decision makers. Business reqs are commonly expressed in terms of measurable objectives and outcomes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fintech</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2019/02/21/fintech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fintech" /><published>2019-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2019/02/21/fintech</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2019/02/21/fintech.html">&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/Fintech.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawing&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px; height:300&quot;/&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fintech or financial technology is often misunderstood as a disruption technology, instead of referring to as &lt;em&gt;integration technology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases, fintech solutions integrate existing systems (both hardware &amp;amp; software). From the perspective of fintech developers, the challenge is integrating new software with the old and existing systems. From the perspective of financial services institutions, the challenge is providing operating platforms that are friendly to developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the financial services sector, fintech can reduce complexity and minimize friction in data-intensive areas such as personal finance, loan origination, cash transfer, consumer banking, capital markets, and equities trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Fintech isn’t just for bankers, brokers, and hedge fund managers. It’s also for merchants and shopkeepers. And increasingly, fintech is for consumers,” says Michael Minelli, Vice President of Commercialization at Mastercard Labs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Hoang Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html">Fintech or financial technology is often misunderstood as a disruption technology, instead of referring to as integration technology.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who is a Business Analyst?</title><link href="/2018/11/10/who-is-a-business-analyst.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who is a Business Analyst?" /><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/11/10/who-is-a-business-analyst</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/11/10/who-is-a-business-analyst.html">&lt;p&gt;From Wikipedia, a BA is someone who analyzes an organization or business domain and documents its business or processes or systems, assessing the business model or its integration with technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From mastersindatascience.org, Business Analyst Responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Establish the objectives and scope of business and IT systems.
Identify multifaceted organizational problems and devise data-driven solutions.
Conduct statistical analyses, surveys, training workshops and tests.
Recommend changes to processes, personnel or product offerings to make internal departments more efficient.
Invent new systems (e.g. stock control) or alter existing ones.
Make specific IT recommendations and support their implementation.
Act as a liaison between management and technical developers (e.g. system architects).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business Analysts lead efforts to define needs and design solutions that deliver value to stakeholder organizations. The complex role utilizes business strategy, operational processes and procedures, requirements management, and subject matter expertise to lead organizations through complex changes. They manage stakeholder expectations, focus on requirements and solutions, measure performance, and, when necessary, suggest and implement corrective actions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hoang Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html">From Wikipedia, a BA is someone who analyzes an organization or business domain and documents its business or processes or systems, assessing the business model or its integration with technology.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Business Of Finance</title><link href="/2018/08/22/the-business-of-finance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Business Of Finance" /><published>2018-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/08/22/the-business-of-finance</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/08/22/the-business-of-finance.html">&lt;p&gt;The world of finance today looks quite different from the world of Mr. Potter’s era. The core institutions remain intact, but the advent of new technologies has produced a financial world in which transactions occur in the blink of an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE SELL SIDE OF FINANCE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;The earlier distinctions between commercial banking and investment 
banking are no longer as defined as they once were. 
The most important lesson in studying the modern financial services
industry is that the sector lines are blurred.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commercial Banking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Commercial banks make their money by securing deposits and lending
the money. As long as the rate of interest paid to depositors is 
lower than the rate of interest charged to the borrowers, the bank
makes money. The lifeblood of the commercial banking industry in the
US is the federal funds rate. This is the rate at which banks and
credit unions lend money overnight to other banks. The rate is
determined by the Federal Reserve Bank’s Federal Open Market Committee,
which meets 8 times per year and sets this rate. The banks are able to
borrow at this rate and, in turn, lend to consumers and businesses at
a higher rate. 

Commercial banks charge all kinds of fees: ATM fees, account maintenance
fees, and application fees. And don’t forget the penalties.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investment Banking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;One of the primary functions of the investment bank is to offer underwriting
services to its clients. The best part about all of this is that the
investment bankers will make a hefty commission on the transaction.

Bankers often advise clients on buying and selling companies. Whether the
banker values a company for sale or for purchase, valuation will form the
cornerstone of the transaction.

Traders will buy and sell securities in blocks and earn commissions on each
trade. Since the traders are dealing with large allocations of securities,
they will rely on salespeople to pitch the trade idea to large institutions.
The trader can add value by finding the best price, which often entails
parceling out individual blocks of the trade or dividing it into smaller
portions. So many large investment banks have sales and trading groups.

One of the most powerful influences in the world of finance is equity research.
Equity research analysts will research entire industries as well as individual
companies that form these industries. The goal of the research analyst is to
provide value-added market insights that allow customers who subscribe to the
research to make smart investment decisions.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retail Brokerage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;One of the oldest businesses in the finance world. Retail brokers, or stockbrokers,
are the good folks who bring Wall Street to Main Street. Brokerage fees dropped
and new technology all but eliminated the need for human resources in the world
of stock purchases.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Hoang Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html">The world of finance today looks quite different from the world of Mr. Potter’s era. The core institutions remain intact, but the advent of new technologies has produced a financial world in which transactions occur in the blink of an eye.</summary></entry></feed>